Well, it can be kind of problematic to
only be able to use post and get
requests because what if we need to do a
put request or a patch request or a
delete request? Um, we wouldn't be able
to do these from our form. And in
addition, um, I told you this form is
going to the wrong location. So, I could
definitely add a correct location by
saying action go to my API at htt
http
col / localhost and it's running on port
5000. And now if I save this and I put
test and data here and I hit submit now
I get an error and that's because this
is sending it across as form data but my
API is expecting it to come across as
JSON and our form is not in valid JSON
format. So, what we'd need to do is we'd
need to be able to take this form and
process it using JavaScript. But if you
noticed, I tried to use JavaScript right
here in this onclick request, and it
keeps getting denied, and it just keeps
skipping straight past the JavaScript.
It console.logs it, but then it goes to
a new page, and so my JavaScript doesn't
have a chance to really run. So, if we
want to fix this, then we need to change
some stuff here on this form. So, what
I'm going to do is I'm going to actually
get rid of all of that right there.
And going to go back and here what I'm
going to do
is I am going to say onsubmit
and this calls a javascript function
when the form submits and I'm going to
call my function um stop form submit.
Now in my script tag I need to write
that function. So I'll say function stop
form submit
and I'm going to receive the event
of the form submitting and I'm going to
say e dot prevent
default.
So now if I save this and I say test
user and I hit submit my hello world
stays. And why? Because we didn't
navigate between pages because this
e.prevent prevent default said rather
than just having the form default and do
its submission to the server, we can go
ahead and stop that. Now that we've
stopped it, we can do whatever we want
with our JavaScript.